

Adrian Perez Zaldivar

- Ca Habana
- □ apzaldivar2014@gmail.com
- **A** +53 58929076

Profile

I am a software engineer with more than 4 years of experience working as a mobile application developer, I am a Computer Science engineer and have spent the last 5 years of my career developing custom mobile applications. I am a proactive professional with experience working within multiple companies.

I am intelligent, autonomous, versatile, I am a good problem solver and I integrate well in the team.

I am eager to learn about new technologies, frameworks and tools, I am proficient in native Android and Flutter. In addition to mobile development, he worked in areas such as database, software design and architecture.

Education

Computer Science Engineering
University of the Informatics Science

Sept 2012 - Jun 2017

Courses

Android Advanced Master: Programming Patterns https://www.udemy.com/course/android-design-patterns/

Master Android Development with Java and Kotlin https://www.udemy.com/course/programacion-android-avanzado/

Android Advanced Course - MVVM as recommended by Google https://www.udemy.com/course/curso-avanzado-android-mvvm/

Flutter Advanced - The next level of mobile development https://www.udemy.com/course/flutter-avanzado/

Personal details

Name Adrián Pérez Zaldivar

Email address apzaldivar2014@gmail.com

Phone number +53 58929076

Address La Habana

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/apzaldivar

Skills

Java
JavaScript
РНР
Dart
Kotlin
Gradle
SQL
Android
Flutter
NodeJS

Employment

Mobile application developer XETID

(Sep 2017 - May 2021)

Roles:

•Senior Android Developer.

Android:

- Development of custom applications.
- Calculation and plotting of optimal routes.
- Calculation of distances between points, polygon areas.
- Management of 3D, vector and raster layers.
- Scanning and generation of QR codes.
- Integration with SocketMobile and Datalogic scanners.
- Management of printers with Bluetooth Low Consumption (BLE).
 - Encryption of credentials and databases.
 - Consumption of REST services.
 - Custom PDF generation module with iTextPDF integration.
- Generation of custom report generation of CSV, EXCEL and XML.
 - Optical Character Recognition, Live Edge Detection.
- Image processing with background tasks (AsyncTask and Threads).
 - Integration with GoogleMaps and MapBox.
 - Firebase Cloud Messaging.
 - Firebase Push Notifications.
 - Pushers.
 - Creation of services.
 - Management of permissions at runtime.
 - Camera management and location.
 - Creation and updating of graphs in real time.
 - Integration with GoogleDrive, GoogleCalendar, GoogleTasks.
 - Google PlayStore administration.

Mobile Application Developer TheCloudGroup

(May 2021 - Dec 2021)

Roles:

Senior Mobile Applications Developer.

Flutter:

- Integration with GoogleMaps and MapBox.
- Firebase Cloud Messaging.
- Firebase Push Notifications.
- · Super base.
- · Creation of services.
- Management of permissions at runtime.
- Camera management and location.
- Creation and updating of graphs in real time.
- · Scanning and generation of QR codes.
- Communication via WebSockets
- Chat in real time.
- Design and layout of interfaces.

Administración de Google PlayStore.

Git
GitLab
Github
Bitbucket
Trello
Asana
Adobe XD
Figma
Figma Postman

Languges

Spanish English

Hobbies

- Learning a new technology
- Listen to music
- Playing soccer

Projects

Project: DocScanner Company: XETID

Date: 2021

Team size: 5 members

Role: Senior Android Developer.

Technologies: Android, OpenCV, REST, Cypher, iTextPDF.

Summary: Project for digitizing documents and uploading to servers in real time using REST services and the OpenCV edge detection library. In this project I played the role of Senior Android Developer and worked with image processing, background threads, databases, role-based authentication and custom PDF

creation.

Project: Inventory Box Company: PALCO GROUP

Date: 2021

Team size: 7 members

Role: Senior Android Developer.

Technologies: Android, REST, QR, Bluetooth, WebSockets, Mapsfor-

Summary: Project for the management of containers, international parcels and deliveries that arrive at the PALCO parcel agency. In this project I worked with microservices, QR scanners, maps and real-time location, routes between points, websockets for real-time communication with the backend, databases, push notifications and other technologies.

Project: SubzeroOrder / SubzeroDelivery

Company: Subzero Inc.

Date: 2021

Team size: 4 members

Role: Senior Android Developer.

Technologies: Android, REST, QR, WebSockets, GoogleMaps,

Canvas.

Summary: E-commerce project for an American ice distribution company, consisting of 2 mobile applications, one for the customer and one for the delivery man. In this project I worked with databases, REST services, two-factor authentication, push notifications, QR readers, websockets, Google MAPS API, screenshot capture using Canvas, and use of the camera API.

Project: DSiMCAF **Company: XETID**

Date: 2021

Team size: 2 members

Role: Senior Android Developer.

Technologies: Android, REST, QR, Bluetooth, Room, Cypher, Digital

Signature, iTextPDF, Adobe XD.

Summary: Inventory control project, developed by me in its entirety, analysis, design, implementation, testing and deployment. This project had a great impact, given that many companies in the country use it, it consists of importing a Database of assets from any statistical system and performing a means check by area, person in charge, location, etc. I worked with REST services, Room-Cypher, digital document signature, custom PDF creation, QR readers, Bluetooth and other technologies.

Project: Metojet

Company: KAMPAR Laboratories

Date: 2020

Team size: 5 members

Role: Senior Flutter Developer.

Technologies: Flutter, Firebase, REST, OAuth 2.0, PDF, Calendar,

Push Notifications.

Summary: Project to control rheumatoid arthritis. In this application you can make appointments with doctors, save a history of metoject doses, define symptoms, observations and adverse reactions to the medication and define reminders for doses. This project was developed using the Google Framework for Hybrid Flutter Applications.

Project: WhoMe

Company: The Cloud Group

Date: 2020

Team size: 4 members

Role: Senior Flutter Developer.

Technologies: Flutter, REST, QR, WebSockets, Stripe, Location,

GoogleMaps.

Summary: Project for the search and offer of jobs. The client can register as an employer or as an employee, filling out a profile, where you expose your skills, you will find someone who employs you in an easy and intuitive way. In this application I used the GoogleMaps API, I used websockets for chat between clients and employers, I used payments with Stripe, I used an identity verification mechanism, REST services, handling of the camera API, reading and generating QR codes, among others.

Project: Reports **Company:** XETID

Date: 2019

Team size: 4 members

Role: Senior Android Developer.

Technologies: Android, REST, QR, VTM-Mapsforge, SQLite. **Summary:** Project to facilitate the reporting of positive and negative incidents associated with services and the quality of life of Cubans. In this project I worked with REST services, Process-Maker, runtime form creation, databases, file download and upload, and offline vector maps.

Project: MapX Company: XETID Date: 2019

Team size: 4 members

Role: Senior Android Developer.

Technologies: Android, REST, Routes, Room, Cypher, VTM-Maps-

forae

Summary: Geographic information system using open source libraries. Maps with multiple layers, vector and raster, calculation

of routes, azimuth, areas, distances, among others.